Guide to the William Reed Gordon transportation records, 1872-1966.
Gordon, William Reed transportation records, 1872-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Reed Gordon transportation records, 1872-1966, 1891-1911 (bulk)
2484
William Reed Gordon, 1899-
1.2 cubic ft.,
Letter impression books, correspondence, orders, bills, receipts, accounts, time-books, insurance policies, broadsides, photographs, timetables, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Primarily letter impression books, loose correspondence, orders, bills, receipts, accounts, time-books, insurance policies, broadsides, photographs of the Ithaca Railway Company; correspondence of general managers directed to equipment manufacturers, and also concerning construction and rental of an apartment house in Cornell Heights under railway sponsorship; form letter from the Duplicate Transfer and Rebate Company of Philadelphis offering to furnish industrial spies; release and decision in a damage case, Bolster v. the Ithaca Street Railway Company, inventory of rolling stock; also, photographs, timetables, and printed items concerning other upstate New York railroads, and steamboats on Cayuga Lake.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Primarily letter impression books (3 v., 1891-95, 1896-97, 1906-10), loose correspondence (1906), orders, bills, receipts, accounts, time-books (2 v., 1903-06), insurance policies, broadsides, photographs of the Ithaca Railway Company; correspondence of general managers directed to equipment manufacturers, and also concerning construction and rental of an apartment house in Cornell Heights under railway sponsorship (1906); form letter (1906) from the Duplicate Transfer and Rebate Company of Philadelphis offering to furnish industrial spies; release and decision in a damage case, Bolster v. the Ithaca Street Railway Company (1904), inventory of rolling stock (1912); also, photographs, timetables, and printed items concerning other upstate New York railroads, and steamboats on Cayuga Lake.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gordon, William Reed, 1899-; Duplicate Transfer and Rebate Company.; Ithaca Street Railway Company.
Subjects:
Business intelligence.; Electric railroads.; Lake steamers.; Railroad accidents.; Railroads--New York.; Steamboats--New York.; Street-railroads--New York--Ithaca.; Transportation--New York.
Form and Genre Terms:
Accounts.; Broadsides.; Inventories.; Photographs.; Timetables.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, July 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Aug. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Sept.-Oct. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, June 1894 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, July 1894 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, Aug. 1894 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, Sept. 1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, Oct.-Dec. 1894 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1895-1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, July-Sept. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, Oct.-Dec. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Accounts, bills, receipts, 1904-1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Bolster v. Ithaca Street Railway Co., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  (79 N.Y. Supp. 597) verifax of decision & original of general release signed by Lucy Bolster
- City Railroad Legislation (dittoed material), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Notes and secondary materials - verifax of movie scenario involving destruction of Ithaca Street Railway car in plunge over Fall Creek Gorge ( 1916 ); Roster of Rolling Stock, June 1, 1912 with MSS notes; 1904 receipt accounts list (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Advertisements for Gordon's books and for Livonia, Avon, Lakeville RR (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Ithaca Street Railway Co. - photographs (1 neg., 2 pos.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Misc. railroads: photograph of Central N.Y. Southern RR (Ithaca-Auburn Shortline); pass for N.Y., Auburn and Lansing RR ( 1910 ); timetable for Ithaca, Auburn and Western Railway ( 1889 ); timetable for trains through Cortland (Erie, N.Y. Central, N.Y. and Ohio Midland, and Syracuse, Binghamton and N.Y. Railroads, 1872 ); timetable (verifax) for L.S. and M. Southern RR (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Steamboats on Cayuga Lake: 1 photograph of Steamer Frontenac 1907, typed copy of newspaper clipping (Aug. 9, 1936 ) re: ferry boat "Busy Bee" (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Post card of hotel at Rogues Harbor, South Lansing, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- BV letterbook [see description of BV, Box 2, #1], 1891-1895 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- BV letterbook, 1896-1897 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  Carbon copies of letters and telegrams sent by Ithaca Street Railway Co. with index to these - includes accounts of & letter to Cornell U. (1897) re: change of location of track near Cascadilla Building
- BV letterbook, 1906-1911 (Box 2, Volume 2)
- BV letterbook, Nov. 1903-May 1906 (Box 2, Volume 3)
- Oversize volume - timebook, May 1903-Aug. 1906 (Volume 1)
- 2 small broadsides (Box 1)
- Photocopy of brochure on Lake Cayuga Transportation Co. (Box 1)
- 4-page mss. list of Cayuga Lake Steam Boats (Box 3)
- Photocopies of several receipts on account with Ithaca Street Railway Co., 2 sheets, June 24, 1897, Dec. 3, 1901 (Box 1)
- List of Traction Books available from Harold E. Cox, Forty Fort, Pa., 1 p., June 1, 1974 (Box 1)
- Advertisement for Third Rails, Pantographs & Trolley Poles (Albany Hudson Fast Line) by Gordon, 1 p. (Box 1)
- 2 post cards of the Bath & Hammondsport R.R. (2 different engines) (Box 1)
- Ithaca Street Railway Miscellany - Bills and checks from 1900 (one small folder) (Box 3)
- Lehigh Valley Railroad, Rochester Junction Station Photograph (8"x10" print, negative in Master Negative File #N874), ca. 1899 (Box 3)